(LOW RUMBLING)
(SONAR BEEPING, ECHOING)
Subtitles by explosiveskull
(SONAR BEEPING,
ENGINE WHIRRING)
(MUFFLED THUMPING)
(SONAR BEEPING, ECHOING)
(ENGINE RUMBLING)
(LOUD CREAKING)
(STEADY BEEPING)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(WIND HOWLING)
(LOW, RAPID BEEPING)
(SONAR BEEPS, ECHOES)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Relax.
Anything in here
would be dead by now.
(BURBLING)
There she is...
the Indominus rex.
(STEADY BEEPING,
MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
♪ ♪
(BEEPING)
(DEEP WHOOSH)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
SUB PILOT (OVER RADIO):
Specimen collected.
Sent to the surface.
Roger that.
Air One, clear for takeoff.
- Begin tracking.
- HELICOPTER PILOT: Copy that.
- Go, go!
- Tracking on.
(RUSTLING, LOW CHITTERING)
(GASPS)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
HELICOPTER PILOT:
Land One, the asset is secure.
We got what we came for.
We're coming back for you.
Close the doors.
Marine One,
I got to close the gates.
Get out of there.
Understood. We're heading out.
(SONAR BEEPING, ECHOING)
Marine One,
I need to close the gates.
Confirm position.
Can you hear me?
Are you out?
Marine One?
- Guys?
- What is that?
(RUSTLING, BRANCHES CRACKING)
(OVER RADIO): Marine One,
I'm closing the gates.
(SLOW, RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
Seriously, guys,
I'm kind of exposed out here.
Marine One,
confirm you're out.
- (MEN SHOUTING)
- Marine One, confirm position.
Can you hear me?
Marine One, where are you?
- He's over there! - Now! Run!
- Look behind you!
I can't reach them!
- MAN: Come on!
- What?!
(DEEP GROWLING)
- (MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
- What is going on?
I can't hear you!
(THUNDER CRASHING)
♪ ♪
(SCREAMING)
(DEEP ROARING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
- Wait! Wait! Wait! Don't go!
- (DEEP ROARING)
- Throw him the ladder!
- (BELLOWING)
Don't go!
Oh! Oh, no!
(BOOMING STEPS)
- (YELLING)
- (BELLOWING)
Aah...!
No! Wait! Don't go!
Oh!
No, no! Aah!
(BELLOWING)
Oh-ho, ye...
Oh! Oh!
Oh, God!
No! No! Aah! Aah!
God, no!
We're gonna stall!
Cut it now!
- Give him a chance!
- We're gonna die here!
Come on!
- Come on!
- No! No! No!
- (GASPING, YELLING)
- (GROWLING)
I said cut it!
Don't do it! Aah!
It's horrible!
(ROARING)
- Yeah!
- (WHOOPING, LAUGHING)
(CONTINUES ROARING)
- ♪ ♪
- (LAUGHING)
(WHOOPING, LAUGHING)
(DEEP ROARING)
(BURBLING)
(MUFFLED BELLOWING)
(PANTING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
- (BEEP)
- DNA sample secure.
Tell the boss
we're coming back home.
(SPLASHING)
(BELLOWING)
♪ ♪
(RUMBLING)
NEWSWOMAN: Three years after
the fall of Jurassic World,
the debate over
Isla Nublar rages on.
The island's
long-dormant volcano,
reclassified as active,
has shown considerable unrest
in recent months.
Geologists now predict
an extinction-level event
will kill off the last
living dinosaurs on the planet.
Since the disaster
that shocked the world in 2015,
the Masrani Corporation
has paid out
more than over 800 million
in damages
to settle class-action lawsuits
brought by survivors.
Activist groups have mobilized
around the globe
in what has become
the flashpoint animal rights
issue of our time.
With an eruption expected
at any moment,
the U.S. Senate has convened
a special committee
to answer
a grave moral question:
Do dinosaurs deserve
the same protections
given to other
endangered species,
- or should they be left to die?
- (BELLOWING)
MALCOLM:
I think that we should allow
our, uh, magnificent
and glorious dinosaurs...
to be taken out by the volcano.
- (GALLERY MURMURING)
- MAN: Murderer.
- SHERWOOD: Silence, please.
- As... as deeply sad
as that would be...
we altered the course
of natural history.
This is a correction.
SHERWOOD: Are you suggesting
the Almighty is...
taking matters
in his own hands?
Senator, with all due respect,
God's not part
of the equation, no.
What I mean is that,
in the last century,
we amassed, uh,
landmark technological power,
and we've consistently
proven ourselves incapable
of handling that power.
80 years ago,
who could have predicted
nuclear proliferation?
But then there it was.
And now we've got
genetic power.
So, how long is it gonna take
for that to spread
around the globe,
and what's
gonna be done with it?
It ain't gonna stop with the
de-extinction of the dinosaurs.
Uh, I'm not sure I know
- what you're talking about.
- (SIGHS)
I'm talking about...
man-made cataclysmic...
change.
What kind of change?
Change is like death.
You don't know
what it looks like
until you're standing
at the gates.
♪ ♪
(ELEVATOR WHIRRING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- ZIA: Your vocal support
would give Congress
a clear message
that dinosaurs are
sentient beings that deserve
to be treated with dignity.
As a matter of fact,
I do have the dinosaurs'
best interests in mind.
- I'm a paleo-veterinarian.
- WOMAN: Is that a real thing?
- That's a real thing.
- You've seen one?
No, I haven't seen one
with my own eyes.
You know, not everyone
can afford to spend
their life savings...
(WHISPERS): Claire.
Oh, uh, hello, hello, um...
- Congresswoman Delgado.
I'm-I'm Claire.
I'm the lead organizer here.
Uh, of course. But if I could
just get a moment of your time?
Great.
Thank you.
Um, so, our mission here
at the Dinosaur Protection
Group is to secure
federal funding for a...
That was, like, 40 seconds.
You're getting better.
You got to stop letting
your mom shop for you.
You don't need
to insult me every time
- someone pisses you off.
- Dude, I'm a doctor,
not a telemarketer.
What is your job again?
You plug in cords, right?
It's actually more important
than it sounds.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Go on.
- Do you have kids?
- Two girls.
Okay. So, your kids,
an entire generation,
has grown up in a world
where dinosaurs
are living and breathing.
But soon they're gonna have
to watch them go extinct...
or not, if people like you
make a difference.
DELGADO:
Set up a meeting with my office
- after the hearing.
- (SIGHS) Great.
Yes!
NEWSWOMAN: We now go live
to the Capitol...
- Claire. It's on.
- MAN: Hey, hey, turn it up.
- WOMAN: Turn it up.
- ...take preventative action
to protect the dinosaurs
on Isla Nublar.
After a thorough deliberations,
the committee has resolved
not to recommend
any legislative action
regarding the de-extinct
creatures on Isla Nublar.
This is an act of God.
And while, of course,
we feel great sympathy
for these animals,
we cannot condone
government involvement
on what amounts
to a privately owned venture.
(TURNS OFF TV)
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
They're all gonna die,
and no one cares.
FRANKLIN:
We do.
(PHONE RINGING)
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
Give me one second.
Let's get back to work.
Okay, everyone, come on.
(SIGHS):
Hello?
WOMAN:
May I speak with Ms. Dearing?
- Yes, this is Claire Dearing.
- Good morning.
I'm calling from
Mr. Benjamin Lockwood's estate.
Would you mind holding
for a second?
Yes, of c...
of course, I'll hold.
♪ ♪
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
Ms. Dearing, you're early.
Would you like to step in?
Thank you.
I will inform Mr. Mills
that you've arrived.
♪ ♪
MILLS:
John Alfred Hammond,
the father of Jurassic Park.
But of course, you know that.
Hello, Claire.
I'm, uh, I'm Eli Mills.
I work for Ben Lockwood.
We actually met once,
seven, eight years ago,
- and you don't remember...
- Of course I remember.
Haven't you run
his foundation since...
Since college, yeah.
Y-You remember?
- Yes.
- Wow. Cool. He, uh...
he wanted someone young
and, uh, idealistic
to spend his fortune...
and I used to be both.
(LAUGHS)
Follow me.
Let me give you
a bit of history.
This is where it all began.
Before the island, Sorna,
Jurassic Park, all of it.
Hammond and Lockwood
built a custom lab
in the subbasement,
extracted the first DNA
from amber
right beneath our feet.
(LAUGHS):
Oh, my goodness.
What they did here
was a miracle.
I still believe that.
So do I, Claire. So do I.
And I still believe it matters
what happens to those animals.
There is something
Mr. Lockwood would very much
like you to do, Claire.
You can call it a favor
for an old friend.
We have a piece of land.
A sanctuary protected
by natural barriers,
fully self-sustaining.
A new home where the dinosaurs
will be secure and free.
CLAIRE:
You're gonna get them out?
You're gonna save them?
LOCKWOOD:
No, Ms. Dearing.
I'm going to save us.
We could both use a touch
of redemption, couldn't we?
Lovely to see you again.
- And you, Mr. Lockwood.
- Hmm.
This was all
John Hammond's dream,
to let these creatures
live in peace.
So we have created sanctuary.
No fences, no cages,
no tourists...
just as Mother Nature intended.
John said it best:
"These creatures don't need
our protection.
They need our absence."
When we were young,
we both shared this passion,
John and I.
What fools we were.
Trying to run
before we'd learned to walk.
As all young men do, I suppose.
But... we learned.
Unfortunately, in the end,
it drove us apart.
Life teaches us
some very hard lessons,
doesn't it, Claire?
Yes.
- Sir Benjamin.
- Hmm?
Ah. My bloody medicines.
Will you excuse me, Claire?
Of course.
Eli here will help you
with the details.
We will save them.
What a gift...
for our children.
(SOFTLY):
Thank you.
Iris.
(LOCKWOOD COUGHS)
Does he have children?
I-I thought I saw...
- Was there a little girl...
- Uh, he has a grandchild.
He's, uh, his daughter died
in a car accident.
- That's awful.
- Yeah, I know.
But they're very close.
Really close.
So what do you need from me?
There was a tracking system
in place at your park...
radio-frequency ID chips
in each dinosaur.
- I remember.
- Right. So if we could access
that system,
our ability to locate
and capture
those animals safely
would increase tenfold.
We need your handprint
to access the system.
But what I really need,
Claire...
is you.
Moving endangered species
isn't exactly legal,
but it's the right thing to do.
No one knows this park
as well as you do,
and we need that expertise.
- How many can you save?
- 11 species, for sure.
I mean, more if we can...
but time is against us.
I'm afraid there is one animal
in particular
that poses
a real challenge for us.
- Blue.
- I didn't know she had a name,
but Blue is potentially
the second most intelligent
piece of life on this planet,
and she's the last of her kind.
She must be preserved.
She can pick up your scent
a mile off...
you'll never capture her.
Well...
we thought you might know
someone who could help.
Maybe you could convince him.
♪ ♪
(EXHALES)
OWEN:
♪ Oh, Time ♪
♪ She is a freight train
chugging ♪
(SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
♪ The light
at the end of the tunnel ♪
♪ Is growing small ♪
♪ Behind you ♪
Hey, Owen.
♪ I still love you ♪
♪ In the morning. ♪
Owen!
Oh, boy.
Hi.
Back for more, huh?
Can I buy you a beer?
Did you bring 'em, or do we
gotta, like, go somewhere?
(CLAIRE LAUGHING LOUDLY)
(CREEDENCE CLEARWATER REVIVAL'S
"DON'T LOOK NOW" PLAYING)
(LAUGHING):
I'm sorry. Seriously?
I can't believe you think
that you left me.
Replay the conversation
in your head, all right?
You said, "You wanna go live
in your van like a bum?
Go ahead, Owen."
And I said, "Okay."
- So how is that you leaving me?
- Because I left. I left you.
You left because I told you to.
And then I left. Because you
didn't wanna live in a van
- on the side of the road, remember?
- No. No, no, no, no.
Because you wouldn't let me
drive the damn van
- for five minutes.
- I'm chivalrous.
- What can I do?
- You are so stubborn.
Well, look at you now.
You're saving the world, so...
Well, I'm trying at least.
You can't just run away
from everything, Owen.
So you're what...
dating an accountant now?
An insurance actuary?
Your skin looks nice.
("DON'T LOOK NOW" CONTINUES)
- Dermatologist?
- Owen...
- Does he check you for moles?
- Stop.
- Ventriloquist?
- This is not why we're here, okay?
Yeah, I know why we're here.
Lockwood's little flunky
called me.
Rescue Op.
Save the dinosaurs
from an island that's about to
explode... what could go wrong?
- I'm going.
- Don't.
- I don't have a choice.
- What? Of course you have a choice.
So what, I should just...
build my own cabin, play pool,
and drink beer all day while
these dinosaurs go extinct?
Yeah.
I like pool.
Blue is alive.
Jesus, Claire.
You raised her, Owen.
You... you spent years
of your life working with her.
You're just gonna let her die?
Well, yeah.
("DON'T LOOK NOW" ENDS)
Come on, you're a better man
than... you think you are.
You should write
fortune cookies.
Forget it, I...
There's a charter flight
leaving tomorrow morning.
You're on the manifest.
I just wanted to let you know.
♪ ♪
(INSECTS CHITTERING, CHIRPING)
- (VELOCIRAPTORS SQUAWKING)
- OWEN: All right, chow time,
chow time.
Whoa, whoa.
Back up. Back off.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Geesh!
- (SQUAWKING)
- Take it easy. Echo.
Geez. There's plenty of food.
God, you guys been eating
sugar or something?
You're hyper today.
(VELOCIRAPTORS
CHOMPING QUIETLY)
Okay, okay.
- (CHATTERING, HISSING)
- Back up. Thank you, Blue.
(SCREECHING)
Whoa, whoa.
(CHATTERING)
Did you get that?
♪ ♪
(SQUAWKS)
ZIA: Relax.
You're more likely to die
riding on a horse
than in a plane.
No, I'm not,
'cause I won't get on a horse.
- My chances are zero.
- Planes are the safest way to travel.
FRANKLIN: You call this
a plane? My cousin has
a drone bigger than this.
♪ ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
IN DISTANCE)
- (GROANS SOFTLY)
- Owen!
Franklin, you wiener,
get on the plane.
Didn't think you
were gonna ever show up.
Oh, um, this is Zia Rodriguez.
- Zia.
- Hey. How you doing?
- Yeah. Real good. How are you?
- Good.
Franklin Webb.
Systems analyst.
- Nervous flyer?
- Would you ride
a thousand-pound horse that's
been abused all its life?
I rode my motorcycle
through the jungle
with a pack of raptors.
We're not compatible.
IRIS (CALLS):
Maisie?
(QUIETLY):
You're always hiding from me.
This is not my job,
looking for you.
Maisie!
(SIGHS)
Maisie?
Come out!
(RUSTLING)
- Boo! (LAUGHING)
- Oh! You silly sausage.
You'll be the death of me.
You know, one day
my heart might really stop.
Then what would you do?
Go and live in the forest
with the lions?
There are no lions
in the forest.
Your grandfather's
been asking for you.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm. So you go see your grandfather, and then
- you go straight to your bath.
- I don't want a bath.
A what?! Queen's English,
girl. "Bath"!
- Bath. Bath.
- Bath.
Bath, not "bath."
You're not a wild animal.
- (ROARS, LAUGHS)
- (YELLS) Stop it.
(MAISIE'S LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
- (KNOCKING)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Hi, Grandpa.
- Ah, there you are.
Come over and sit by me.
- I've missed you.
- I was on safari all the way
through the Cretaceous
to the Jurassic in one day.
- Oh, my. What'd you see?
- Mostly herbivores.
There was one T. rex, though.
Casualties, of course.
Iris included.
- She jumped out of her skin.
- (LOCKWOOD CHUCKLES)
You have your mother's
wicked sense of humor.
♪ ♪
Do I look like her?
Oh, yes.
You could be her mirror image.
Did my mother
ever visit the park?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Once...
a long time ago.
She would have saved them,
too, you know.
She would have saved them all.
♪ ♪
(ANIMALS SQUAWKING)
(RUMBLING)
♪ ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
WHEATLEY:
Claire.
Ken Wheatley. Welcome back.
Quite an operation
you've got going on here.
Mr. Lockwood takes
his humanitarian efforts
very seriously.
Where's the, uh,
raptor wrangler?
Animal behaviorist.
- Owen Grady.
- Hey, Owen. Ken Wheatley.
And you are...
Great White Hunter?
(CHUCKLES):
I guess.
I'm the expedition facilitator.
FRANKLIN:
Oh, God!
It's hot!
It's about to get
a whole lot hotter.
♪ ♪
Keep it moving!
You're all clear!
Go! Go, you've got
the green light!
This way, let's go!
Let's go! Keep it moving!
Hold it! Hold up!
(RHYTHMIC BUZZING)
(SOLDIER SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
Need some bug spray?
Bug spray?
The T. rex would be dead
by now, right?
ZIA: No. It's impossible
to know the max lifespan
of a clone in a completely
different environment.
Take a caveman that would
have lived 20 years, feed him
prime meals,
give him health care,
he's gonna live...
five times as long.
So she'd be dead by now.
Right?
(RHYTHMIC BUZZING)
♪ ♪
WHEATLEY:
Bad memories?
Some were good.
(THUNDERING BOOM IN DISTANCE)
(ENGINE TURNS OFF)
What was that?
(THUNDERING BOOM IN DISTANCE)
Is it the T. rex?
(THUNDERING BOOMING,
DEBRIS CLATTERING)
I have to see this.
Hey. Miss?
Miss!
This area's not secured.
(THUNDERING BOOM)
(BELLOWING)
(DINOSAUR GROWLING)
(THUNDERING STEPS)
(BELLOWING)
(CRUNCHING)
ZIA:
Look at that.
Never thought I'd see one
in real life.
She's beautiful.
(BELLOWING)
Can we...?
♪ ♪
Okay, let's go.
(GRUNTS)
Okay, okay.
Okay, main system.
- Turn on control.
- (LOW RUMBLING)
- It should be working.
- (RUMBLING GROWING LOUDER)
- (BOOMING)
- (ANIMALS SQUAWKING)
WHEATLEY:
Come on, tiger.
- You know what you're doing?
- (BEEPING)
After you, tiger.
ZIA: Are we sure
these biometric chips
are still transmitting?
Battery would be dead by now.
- All right.
- CLAIRE: The dinosaur is the battery.
They're powered
by body heat and movement.
- (SNAPS FINGERS)
- Hand.
CLAIRE:
How much longer until...
(THUMPING, WHIRRING)
FRANKLIN:
I'm in.
(LOW BEEPING)
FRANKLIN: There's a large
concentration on the east dock.
That's our boat... we've already
captured a bunch of 'em.
- Without the tracking system?
- The big herbivores
are easy to find.
Can you isolate that raptor?
- I need a species code.
- D-nine.
There she is. I'm gonna need
to borrow your truck.
I'm coming with you...
we don't know
what kind of condition
she might be in.
Miss, things could get hairy
out there.
These are powerful sedatives.
One too many, and she
could have respiratory failure.
Also, I'm not
as soft and witless
as your comment implies.
Let's go, beefcake.
Oh, Owen?
Be careful, okay?
♪ ♪
If I don't make it back...
remember...
you're the one
who made me come.
- I'll be all right.
- (COCKS GUN)
- (DISTANT RUMBLING)
- (EXCITED SQUAWKING)
We're not gonna get any closer
to her in this thing.
- We should stop here.
- Hold up!
Load out, look alive,
stay alive.
- We got your back, brother.
- Yeah.
OWEN (OVER RADIO): Claire, I'm
gonna have to track her alone.
I'll need you to be my eyes
if she runs. Copy?
Copy that.
(RHYTHMIC BEEPING)
(DISTANT THUNDER ROLLING)
(SCREECHING IN DISTANCE)
(SCREECHING)
(SQUAWKING)
(SQUAWKING FADES IN DISTANCE)
(DISTANT BOOMING)
Wheatley, I'm on fresh sign.
Wait for my signal.
(DISTANT RUMBLING)
There you are.
(SCREECHING)
- (HISSING)
- Hey, girl. You miss me?
- (SQUAWKS)
- Easy. Hey!
- (HISSES)
- Hey.
- (CHITTERS)
- I brought you something.
(BELLOWS)
- (HISSING)
- Here you go.
That's right.
(LOW GROWLING)
Okay.
- (SCREECHES)
- Hey.
(HUFFS, HISSES)
(GRUNTS, GROWLS)
You know me.
Eyes on me.
- (GRUNTS, HUFFS)
- Yeah.
- (LOW GROWLING)
(WHISPERS):
Yeah.
You know me.
That's right.
- (SNIFFING)
- That's right.
Hold your...
(GRUNTS)
(SCREECHING)
I told you to wait
for my signal!
(GUNS COCKING)
(GROWLING, SCREECHING)
(QUIETLY):
Back your men up right now.
(LOW GROWLING)
(SCREECHES)
(GRUNTING, YELLING)
(SNARLS)
No, hey, no, no,
don't shoot her!
- (SCREAMS)
- (GUNSHOT)
(SCREECHES)
(SEETHING EXHALE)
Wheatley, you son of a bitch!
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Owen! What are you doing?!
Owen.
(BLUE BELLOWING WEAKLY)
You shoot me...
and that animal dies.
I think we have the drop
on you, sweetheart.
She's losing blood,
and if I don't treat her...
she'll never make it
back to camp.
(EXHALES)
How about this?
That animal dies, I shoot you.
You're gonna take care of her.
Let's move out!
♪ ♪
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING)
(DEBRIS CLATTERING)
(BOTH SCREAM)
MAN (IN DISTANCE):
Cut the cord and let's go!
Let's get out of here!
♪ ♪
(BEEPING)
(THUMPING, CLACKING)
No! No! No!
No, wait!
(CLAIRE GRUNTING)
Wait, a-are they protecting us?
What's going on?
(BEEP)
I don't think so.
(BOOMING)
(FRANKLIN YELLS)
Why am I here?!
WHEATLEY:
Hey, Mills, we got her done!
Mission accomplished!
(LAUGHS)
Just in the nick of time.
Wheatley, what the hell
is going on there?
We're a day
behind schedule already.
WHEATLEY:
I want that money in the bank
- by the time I get back, all right?
- Okay, good.
Listen to me,
no more delays, okay?
- Mr. Mills?
- If we don't get those animal...
Not now, Maisie, thank you.
If we don't get those...
- Mr. Mills, are the dinosaurs safe...
- I said not now!
WHEATLEY:
Mills?! Mills?!
I'm sorry, honey.
This is an important call.
If you go up to the library,
- I'll meet you up there in a few minutes.
- Okay.
Okay, I'll tell you
all about it, I promise.
- Okay.
- Okay. Okay.
Wheatley...
you get those animals here now.
I want that bonus.
We got the blue one.
- (LOW GROANING)
- MILLS: Bring her to me first!
WHEATLEY:
All right.
(BOOMING)
(THUNDERING STEPS)
(DINOSAUR HUFFING)
(INSECTS BUZZING)
(DINOSAUR GROWLS)
(OWEN GRUNTING QUIETLY)
(LOW GROWLING)
(DISGUSTED GROANING)
- (CONTINUES GROANING)
- (BOOMING STOMP)
(HIGH-PITCHED GRUNT)
(ROARS)
(BOOMING STOMP)
(OWEN GROANING)
(LOW GRUNTING)
- (GROWLING)
- (GASPING, GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING, STRAINING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING, GRUNTING)
No.
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
(GASPS)
(YELLS)
(STRAINED GRUNT)
♪ ♪
Hello? Can anyone hear me?
- Hello?
- (COMPUTER BEEPING)
Hello? Is anybody there?
Can anybody copy?
(GRUNTS)
I'm-I'm trying everything.
It's jammed.
"Just take the job, son,
build your people skills."
- Yeah, thanks, Dad.
- (COMPUTER CHIMING)
That's it.
- (DOORS CLANK)
- (ALARM CHIRPING)
Proximity alert.
- Something's coming.
- Where does that tunnel lead?
Well, it connects
to the rest of the...
- (DEEP GROWL IN DISTANCE)
- ...park.
(ALARM CONTINUES CHIRPING)
FRANKLIN: It's the T. rex.
It's the T. rex.
Claire, it's the T. rex.
Will you stop?
It's not the T. rex.
- Probably.
- "Probably"?
(GASPS)
Lava! Lava!
- (DEEP GROWLING)
- Lava. Lava.
Deep breaths, Franklin.
- (ROARING)
- (CLAIRE GASPS)
(ROARING)
(GASPING)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(ROARING)
(HIGH-PITCHED SCREAMING)
- See?! Not a T. rex!
- How is this better?!
(ROARING)
- (LAVA HISSING)
- (ROARS)
(ROARING)
Claire, what do we do?!
What do we do?!
(GRUNTING)
It's stuck!
Chair!
(GASPING)
(DEEP GROWLING)
Come on! Let's go!
Come on, Franklin!
- We made it! Yeah!
- (LADDER CREAKING)
- (ROARING)
- (HIGH-PITCHED SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on!
- Come on, come on, come on!
- (ROARING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Yes, yes, go, go! Go, go!
- (GASPING)
- (DEEP RUMBLING)
Claire.
Holy sh...
OWEN (IN DISTANCE):
Run!
- Run!
- (DINOSAURS CHIRPING)
(DINOSAURS BELLOWING)
(BOTH GASPING)
OWEN:
Run!
(SQUAWKING)
- (CLAIRE GASPS)
- (FRANKLIN YELLS)
(HIGH-PITCHED SCREAM)
(BELLOWING)
(CLAIRE SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(HEAVY THUMP)
Go, go!
- Okay, okay. Okay.
- Buckle up, Franklin.
Get in!
(ROARING)
(DEEP GROWLING)
(FRANKLIN SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
(VOLCANO RUMBLING)
(THUNDERING BOOM)
Owen!
(DINOSAURS BELLOWING,
SHRIEKING)
(BELLOWING,
SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED BELLOWING)
(TRUMPETING)
- CLAIRE: We got to get out.
- We just fell from the cliff.
We're alive. We're alive.
Franklin, move.
- No. No, no, no!
- (WATER HISSING)
No. Claire, we're gonna sink!
Water's leaking!
- Oh. Oh, God!
- (LAVA THUMPING ON GLASS)
We need to get out!
(SCREAMS)
Franklin, watch out!
I want to go home!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- Owen! Owen!
- Owen?
Owen. Okay.
Move! Move!
No! No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
Push!
(GRUNTING)
Owen! No, no.
FRANKLIN:
Where's he going?
CLAIRE:
Okay. Okay, don't panic.
- Don't panic.
- We're running out of air.
- We're not gonna make it.
- We are. We are.
Take a deep breath.
(GASPS)
(MUFFLED BELLOWING)
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
♪ ♪
(GASPING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(COUGHING, GASPING)
- Where is Zia?
- It was a double-cross.
They took her.
She must be with Blue.
Hey, can you still track 'em?
Not anymore.
It was a lie.
Bastards! It was all a lie!
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(ROARING)
Not all of it.
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
Move it! Move! Move!
Anything of value,
I want on that boat!
- How you doing?!
- MAN: The bolt won't give!
Well, just button it up,
and we'll tow it on! Let's go!
(ROARING)
- (BELLOWING)
- Come on, now.
(SNARLING)
(SQUAWKING)
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
Hang on! Wait up!
Stop that truck! Stop it!
(LOW GRUMBLING)
Hey, sweetheart.
Hello, hello.
(BELLOWING)
Beautiful.
You're gonna feel that
when you wake up.
ZIA:
Hey, put your weapon down!
You got the barrel pointed
right at her head!
- Hey, Wheatley!
- OWEN: They have Zia.
They're loading out.
If they already had the
dinosaurs, why do they need us?
They needed the tracking system
to capture Blue.
OWEN: There she is.
She don't look good.
(RUMBLING)
We need to get on that boat.
The rock's good.
We're safe on the rock.
It's the boat or the lava,
Franklin.
All right, boat's good.
I'm all about the boat.
(MEN SHOUTING)
Go, go, get on the boat!
Get on the boat now! Go, go!
Move it, move it!
(LAVA WHOOSHING, WHISTLING)
Get that truck!
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
Franklin!
- Hey, get that truck going!
- Okay.
- You okay?
- Am I dead?
Not yet, kid.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Come on!
Give me your hand! Reach!
Come on, reach!
(GASPS)
Hold on!
(YELLING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(PANTING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (ALARM BUZZING, RINGING)
(DINOSAUR BELLOWING)
♪ ♪
(DISTANT BELLOWING)
- (BELLOWING CONTINUES)
- (TREMBLING BREATH)
(BELLOWING)
♪ ♪
(BELLOWING CONTINUES)
(DOOR THUDS HEAVILY)
♪ ♪
(RADAR BEEPING STEADILY)
- (INTERCOM BEEPS)
- IRIS: Mr. Mills?
Your visitor's waiting.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
MILLS:
Mr. Eversoll.
It's a pleasure
to meet you in person
after all this time.
How are ya?
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
- Where are the dinosaurs?
- The dinosaurs are, uh,
are en route.
Oh, so am I supposed
to sell these ones?
Look, you don't need
to worry, okay?
They will be here soon.
I-I don't really
work with amateurs,
so I'm gonna contact my buyers
and call this off.
They will be here tomorrow,
and your buyers
won't be disappointed.
Trust me,
whatever their interest...
agricultural,
industrial, sport hunting...
we will have something
to suit them.
11 species, each with unique
biopharmaceutical properties.
I estimate
four million per species.
Four million is a slow Tuesday
where I'm from.
You're wasting my time.
You ever made a hundred million
on a Tuesday?
- (LAUGHS)
- Huh?
All this is in the past.
I want to talk to you
about the future.
I'll give you ten minutes.
The whole point of selling
the Isla Nublar dinosaurs
is to finance
our future operations here.
It's, uh, seed money.
Call it a-an overture to
something much more ambitious.
EVERSOLL: Yeah,
and more lucrative, I guess.
Right. We've reactivated
the old facilities,
updated the technology,
and imported
the best geneticists
from around the world.
This operation has been
many years in the planning.
Genetic power is
an uncharted frontier.
The potential for growth
is more than you can fathom.
This way, please.
If the entire run
of our sorry history
has taught us
one irrevocable lesson,
it's that man is
inevitably drawn to war
and is willing to use
any means necessary to win it.
- You're gonna weaponize them?
- We've been using animals
in combat for centuries.
Horses, elephants.
The Soviets used
disease-bearing rats
- against the Germans at Stalingrad.
- Yes, yes.
Our geneticists have created
a direct descendant
of Henry Wu's masterpiece,
the animal that took down
Jurassic World.
Indominus rex.
Her DNA,
retrieved from the island
way before its destruction,
forms the architecture
of a completely new creature.
Every bone and muscle designed
for hunting and killing.
And thanks
to Owen Grady's research,
it follows human command.
We call it...
the Indoraptor.
(DOOR CREAKS QUIETLY)
- (WHISPERS): Grandpa?
- (DOOR CREAKS SHUT)
Grandpa?
- (SNORTS SOFTLY)
- (GASPS)
Grandpa.
Maisie?
What are you doing up?
There was a man here today
with Mr. Mills.
It was probably
just some business
about the sanctuary,
that's all.
I heard them talking...
they're going
to sell the dinosaurs.
They're bringing them here.
Well...
I'm sure you misunderstood.
- I know what I heard, Grandpa.
- Maisie,
it's way past your bedtime.
Let's talk about this
in the morning.
- But...
- Maisie, I'll find out tomorrow.
Go to bed.
Good night.
Good night, my heart.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
♪ ♪
(RUMBLING, BOOMING)
(DINOSAUR BELLOWING)
(SQUAWKING, CHITTERING)
- (GROWLS)
- Oh! Jesus.
(SQUEAKY GRUNTING)
(RAPID HUFFING)
- (GROANS SOFTLY)
- (THUMPING)
(SQUAWKING)
It's okay, Blue.
Just a little longer.
Oh, my God!
You guys are alive! You...
Oh, look what
they've done to her.
- Who are these assholes?
- Animal traffickers.
Look how they're treating them.
They're not gonna take 'em
to a sanctuary,
they're gonna sell them.
Not Blue. They need her
for something else.
- Like what?
- I don't know, but she's...
she's hemorrhaging,
and I don't have instruments,
and they want to keep her alive.
- Hey. Shh...
- (BLUE PANTING)
- (COOING)
- You're all right. You're all right.
ZIA:
Claire, come here.
Come on.
Put your hand here.
Steady pressure.
- (SCREECHES)
- Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
Watch out.
I can't take the bullet out
without a transfusion
from another animal.
- Which one of you knows how to find a vein?
- Oh.
- I-I did a blood drive for the Red Cross.
- Great.
Okay. Franklin,
take over for Claire.
No, no, no, no, no, no...
Franklin. Now.
- Steady pressure.
- (BELLOWING)
(GASPS)
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Is it in my mouth? Did it get in my mouth?
- Mm-mm.
- You sure?
- You're good.
All of the animals
should be sedated.
Look for any kind of tetanuran.
Their blood type
should be close enough.
Look for carnivores
with two or three fingers.
No more than three.
I think there's one on board.
(SLOW, DEEP BREATHING)
(INSECTS BUZZING)
You got to be kidding me.
(SNORTS)
(GASPS)
(INSECTS BUZZING)
She's tranqued.
Okay, okay.
Okay, I got it.
Come on.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
- (CLAIRE GASPS)
- (METALLIC BANG)
- (OWEN GRUNTS)
- Are you okay?
(STRAINED):
I'm okay.
Come on.
You're gonna have to do it.
I can't, I...
the skin is too thick.
I have to use both my hands
to put pressure on the vein.
You got to do it.
I-I can't. I can't reach.
You're gonna have to
climb up there.
Oh, I'm not...
(SCOFFS)
No, no.
I'm not gonna climb up there.
You'll be okay.
It's like riding a bull.
"Riding a bull"?
I didn't grow up in a rodeo
- or wherever you came from.
- She's asleep now.
I can't say that she's gonna
be asleep a minute from now,
so get up.
Okay, fine.
Oh, my God, she stinks.
Jesus.
- (GRUNTS)
- Gently. Gently!
(GROWLS)
(CHUCKLES)
Good job.
You're making this look
totally normal.
(CHUCKLES)
You're gonna have to
jam it in there.
It's really thick skin.
- Mm-hmm. Yeah.
- Ready?
- Okay. One...
- One...
- Two...
CLAIRE:
Stab!
- (GROWLS)
- Oh, shoot.
- Hey!
- (GASPS) Owen!
(GRUNTS)
Oh...
Oh.
It's working.
- (CHUCKLES)
- (MEN LAUGHING NEARBY)
MAN:
The pee is silent.
MAN 2:
That door is open.
MAN 3:
I got it.
(GROWLS SOFTLY)
(ROARS)
OWEN:
Shit!
(GASPS)
The bars!
The bars, Owen. Owen,
I can get through there.
Come on.
(GRUNTS)
(ROARING)
(ROARS)
Jump, Owen!
(ROARS LOUDLY)
Owen, jump.
- Now!
- (GRUNTS)
(BOTH PANTING)
Did you see that?
Please tell me
you got the blood.
- (BLOOD SLOSHING)
- (RUMBLING GROWL)
♪ ♪
(DOOR OPENS)
(BEEPING)
(DOORS HISS)
(BEEPS)
♪ ♪
(DINOSAUR CHITTERS ON VIDEO)
OWEN (OVER SPEAKERS):
This is Delta.
She's one of
the holdover theropods,
one of the survivors
from the second group.
Now, watch this.
I show any sign of weakness
whatsoever...
(MOCK WHIMPERING)
(SHRIEKING)
See that?
Day 176.
Blue is showing
unprecedented levels
of compliance.
Here I am with Blue.
She's a theropod
from the new group.
- (CHITTERS)
- I show signs of weakness...
(MOCK WHIMPERING)
(PURRING)
(CHITTERS)
Hey.
- I'm okay.
- (CHITTERS)
(CHUCKLES):
She...
she's pretty extraordinary.
(BEEPS)
OWEN:
Blue, displaying levels
of interest, concern,
hyper-intelligence, uh,
cognitive bonding.
See that?
She's tilting her head.
She's craning forward. Sh...
Increased eye movement...
she's curious.
- She's showing empathy.
- (CHITTERS)
ZIA: Okay,
I'm gonna make an incision
in her leg
to remove the bullet.
(SHRIEKS)
It's a lot of muscle tissue.
(EXHALES)
- (CHITTERS)
- (LAUGHING)
(SHUSHES)
(ZIA BREATHING SHALLOWLY)
She's gonna be okay.
(CRYING)
(LAUGHS)
- (LAUGHS SOFTLY)
- OWEN: Blue is the key.
(CHITTERS, SNEEZES)
Bless you.
You have Blue, you get
these raptors to do anything.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- MAN: You're sure she'll live?
MILLS: If it dies,
we have blood samples.
MAN: No, no, no.
That's not good enough.
The raptor is
a behavioral specimen.
We need her in good health.
I didn't shoot the damn thing.
What do you want me to do, huh?
You don't have
the faintest comprehension
of what I'm doing here.
Do you understand
the complexity of creating
an entirely new
- life-form?
- Uh, no, but I understand
the complexity
of paying for it, okay?!
HENRY: All your money
will have been wasted
if I don't get Blue here
in good health.
To get the next iteration
under control,
it needs to form
a familial bond
with a closely-related
genetic link.
- English, Henry.
- It needs a mother!
(GASPS)
Blue's DNA will be part of
the next Indoraptor's makeup.
So it will be genetically coded
to recognize her authority
and assume her traits.
Empathy, obedience...
everything the prototype
you have now is missing.
Okay, so how long
is this gonna take?
(SCOFFS)
It's not a sprint, Mr. Mills.
It's a marathon.
A marathon sounds expensive.
Besides, time is running out
and so is my patience, Henry.
HENRY:
You have to understand,
this is all
uncharted territory.
A wolf, genetically,
is barely distinguishable
from a bulldog,
but within that gray area...
is art.
MILLS: (GROANS)
Spare me the poetry, Henry.
Can you do it?
HENRY:
Yes, I can do it.
MILLS:
Well, then do it.
HENRY:
Thank you.
MILLS:
God, you're a pain in the ass.
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
(ROARING)
- Hey! Hey!
- (WHIMPERING)
- Maisie!
- (GROWLING)
What is that?
What is it?!
(GRUNTS)
Keep her in there
and keep the door locked.
You want to keep her locked in?
That's exactly what I want.
Sir Benjamin needs
to see you now.
I believe it's important.
♪ ♪
- (SHIP HORN BLOWS)
- (GASPS)
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
MAN:
Put it on line!
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
IN DISTANCE)
(SNIFFS)
- (SHIP HORN BLOWS)
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
MAN (OVER SPEAKERS):
All crew prepare for docking.
MAN 2:
Look alive, soldiers!
- All crew prepare for docking.
- MAN 3: Let's go, let's go!
MAN 3:
Let's move it, boys.
(SHOUTING CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY)
We're here.
Where?
WHEATLEY:
Get in your truck and let's go.
- Move, move.
- Move, move, move.
You got a heartbeat?
Yeah. Do you?
I need blood samples.
I'm not here to help you
reset the food chain, so...
take your own damn samples.
(SIGHS)
What a nasty woman.
Go, go, now, now. Go.
MAN (OVER SPEAKER): Attention,
all crew. Attention, all crew.
Drivers, get to your vehicles.
Hey! What the hell's going on?
- I was, um...
- I need an extra pair of hands.
- He volunteered.
- You deck crew?
Aye, aye.
We're loading out.
Follow me.
Uh, does that mean we're
leaving the ship right now?
That is what
"loading out" means.
Now get moving.
Come on, follow me.
Come on, kid.
- Shit.
- There's lots to do.
- Get a move on, come on.
- CLAIRE: Oh, no.
He's not gonna make it.
- Move it! Come on, move!
- CLAIRE: We have to help him.
Stay here. I'll get him.
- (ENGINE STARTS)
- There's no time.
Let's go.
♪ ♪
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
MAN:
Good to go!
MAN 2:
Roll out.
Where are they taking them?
We're about to find out.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
- (ENGINE STARTS)
- MAN: Let's go!
(MEN SHOUTING)
ZIA:
Come on, girl.
- (SHRIEKS)
- Whoa!
Yes!
This is Lockwood's estate.
He must have
one big-ass garage.
♪ ♪
- (TRUCK BEEPING)
- MAN: Come on!
We want this offloaded
in ten mikes.
(MEN SHOUTING)
(ROARING)
- (ROARING)
- Hit him!
(GOAT BLEATING)
(ROARS)
(LOUD ROARING)
LOCKWOOD:
Did you really think
you could get away with it?
In my own house.
You entrusted me
to guide your fortune
into the future.
I have done that.
Damn you!
Pick up that phone.
I want you to call the police.
It'll be easier if the story
comes from you.
As you say, sir.
You know, I've been thinking,
John Hammond was right.
(PHONE BEEPS)
It was an unholy thing
that you did.
I'm not the only
guilty one here, am I, sir?
♪ ♪
Hey.
We hit that town,
we call the cavalry,
shut this down.
(GUN COCKS)
(OWEN GASPS)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Hello.
You should have stayed
on the island.
Better odds.
- (GUNS COCKING)
- (GASPS)
MILLS:
Hi, Claire.
I just wanted to come
and apologize.
I didn't want to bring you
into any of this,
but it was the only way that
we could get the raptor.
- (OWEN GRUNTS)
- We needed it.
- Come on.
- (CLAIRE HUFFS)
So, what?
This is it?
I mean, you're a smart guy.
You could have
started a foundation,
cured cancer,
but instead you... what?
Sell endangered species?
I saved these animals.
You betrayed a dying man
for money.
Claire, I admire your idealism,
but we both exploited
these animals.
At least I have the integrity
to admit it.
I never, ever did anything
remotely illegal.
You authorized the creation
of the Indominus rex.
You exploited a living thing
in a cage for money.
How is that different?
Huh? And you.
The man who proved raptors
can follow orders.
You never thought about
the applications
of your research, Owen?
How many millions a trained
predator might be worth?
You two, you're the parents
of the new world.
(GROANS)
Hey!
- Let him go.
- Owen.
I think I'll break it.
Let him go.
(MILLS GROANS)
- Claire, I just want... aah!
- (METALLIC CLANG)
(OWEN CHUCKLING)
Say, how we gonna end this?
Well, as far as everybody else
is concerned,
they burned up on the island.
MAN (OVER RADIO):
Buyers on approach.
Looks like a full house.
MAN 2:
Roger that.
♪ ♪
(WIND WHOOSHES SOFTLY)
EVERSOLL:
Good evening.
MILLS:
Good evening. Good evening.
- Welcome, gentlemen. Welcome.
- Good evening.
Ah, and these guys
are development rep
for Aldaris Pharmaceuticals.
- Great.
- And the guy in the beard
is a proxy for Gregor Adlrich,
the Slovenian arms dealer.
EVERSOLL: Uh, equine buyers
for Rand Magnus,
an oil magnate from Houston.
MILLS: Well, what-what's
their interest?
Strictly personal.
His kid wants
a baby triceratops.
Glenn, how's Janet?
- GLENN: She's doing fine, thanks.
- (CHUCKLES)
EVERSOLL:
Straight ahead, Glenn.
(PANTING QUIETLY)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
(CONVERSATION CONTINUES
IN RUSSIAN)
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
Well, he only wants carnivores.
Two of them.
EVERSOLL: Looks like Lockwood's
gonna have a very good night.
Will he be joining us?
MILLS:
Um, that's very unlikely.
♪ ♪
(WIND HOWLS)
(WHISPERS):
Grandpa?
Grandpa.
Grandpa, wake up.
Grandpa?
- Grandpa, wake up. Wake up.
- (FLATLINING TONE)
MILLS (IN DISTANCE):
Iris!
(FOOTSTEPS NEARBY)
MILLS:
It's over.
What a tragedy.
I suppose now he's gone,
you'll be looking
for another situation.
No.
Maisie needs me.
MILLS:
I'm her guardian now.
What she needs is
no longer your concern.
IRIS:
You don't understand her
the way I do.
MILLS:
I understand her value.
But I raised her.
I raised...
- both of them.
- (GASPS SOFTLY)
- Please, Mr. Mills...
- Good-bye, Iris.
♪ ♪
(MUFFLED CREAKING, SQUEAKING)
(CREAKING, SQUEAKING CONTINUES)
(BELLOWING IN DISTANCE)
(GROANING, LOW GRUNTING)
CLAIRE:
Do you remember the first time
you saw a dinosaur?
First time you see them,
it's like...
a miracle.
You read about them in books,
you see the bones in museums,
but you don't
really believe it.
They're like myths.
And then you see...
the first one alive.
(LOW, SQUEAKY GRUNTS)
(DEEP EXHALE)
This is not your fault.
But it is.
No.
This one's on me.
I showed 'em the way.
Well, listen, you and I
are gonna have plenty of time
- to talk about this later.
- If there is a later.
Yes, there is.
(BELLOW IN DISTANCE)
I got a cabin to finish.
(LOUD THUMP)
(GRUNTING, SNORTING NEARBY)
CLAIRE:
What is that?
(GRUNTING)
Well, look who just woke up.
(WHISTLES)
Boo.
(SNARLING, SCREECHING)
(DINOSAUR GROANS)
We're getting out of here.
Welcome...
ladies, gentlemen,
to this extraordinary evening.
Let's dive right in
with lot number one...
the ankylosaurus.
(AMAZED GASPS)
(GROWLING)
- (BELLOW)
- She's a herbivorous quadruped,
- MAN: I'll be damned!
- late Cretaceous.
This is one of
the largest armored dinosaurs,
known by paleontologists
- (BELLOWS)
- as a living tank.
- (SHOCKED MURMURING)
- (GROWLING)
- (WHISTLES)
- (POUNDING STEPS)
(LOUD THUMP)
What are you doing?
Escaping.
- You sure about this?
- Nope. (WHISTLES)
- (GROWLING)
- (LOUD THUMP)
I have $4 million.
Anyone with five?
- MAN: $5 million.
- $5 million.
$5 million.
Do I hear six?
- MAN: $6 million!
- $6 million. Thank you.
Any increase on six... Seven.
- $7 million.
- $8 million, now!
$8 million.
$9 million on the phones.
Do I hear $10 million?
- $10 million? $10 million?
- Ten!
$10 million!
Once, twice...
Sold... to the gentleman
- from Indonesia.
- (APPLAUSE)
Congratulations, sir.
- (WHISTLES)
- (GROWLING)
Lot number two,
ladies and gentlemen.
- (SCREECHING)
- (EXCITED CHATTER)
A juvenile...
- allosaurus.
- (ROARS)
- (YELLING, EXCITED CHATTER)
- (CHUCKLES) A fierce...
and an aggressive predator.
(SNARLS)
- (WHISTLES)
- (GRUNTING)
Sold!
(OWEN WHISTLES)
Wonderful.
Wonderful bidding.
(SNARLS)
(BELLOWING, GROWLING)
- You're good. Let's go.
- Move it out.
- Here we go.
- Bring it on back. Let's go.
(WHISTLES)
(POUNDING STEPS)
- (GRUNTS)
- OWEN (SOFTLY): Hey. Hey.
CLAIRE:
Okay.
Hey. Hey, you.
- (GRUNTING)
- Look at me. Look at me.
Hey!
Come with me. Come with me.
Okay. There you go.
(WHISTLES)
- (CLANG)
- (PAINED GRUNT)
(GROANS)
You're welcome.
(SQUEAKY WHIMPERING,
LOW GRUNTING)
(CLATTERING IN DISTANCE)
(MAISIE'S TREMBLING BREATH)
CLAIRE:
Hey!
Wait! Please! Please wait.
(PANTING, CRYING)
(WHISPERS): That's
Lockwood's granddaughter.
Hey.
Hey, kid. You want
to come down out of there?
- Uh...
do you remember me?
- (SHUDDERING)
- Yeah?
My name is Claire.
What's yours?
Maisie.
- Maisie Lockwood.
- Oh, Maisie.
Well, this is my friend, Owen.
(CRYING):
I saw you
with the velociraptors.
Uh, Blue.
Oh. Oh, yeah?
Uh... y-you like dinosaurs?
Hey, so do I.
Tell you what,
you come on down from there,
I'll tell you everything you
need to know about Blue, huh?
That sound all right?
All right, yeah.
Come on down.
Sweetie...
we need some help
finding your grandfather.
Can you take us to him?
(SNIFFLES)
No.
You made it down here
all by yourself, huh?
Brave kid. Looks like
you could use a friend.
He's gone.
(SNIFFLES)
Uh...
so, listen, I'll tell you what,
we were just about to go
and find our friends
and then get
the heck out of here.
You want to come with us?
CLAIRE:
We could use a friend, too.
MAN:
Nineteen-five!
EVERSOLL (IN DISTANCE):
19.5 right here.
Do I hear 20? Do I hear 20?
20? Thank you.
Thank you. 20.
- Do I hear...
- 21!
$21 million!
$21 million...
- (GAVEL BANGS)
- Sold!
- (APPLAUSE)
- And now, ladies and gentlemen,
that we are halfway
through the evening...
(LOW GROWLING)
...we'd like to offer
a special treat
to our...
discriminating buyers.
This evening we will preview
- (LOW GROWLING)
- a new asset
that we've been developing.
A creature of the future
made from pieces of the past.
(EXCITED CHATTER)
Ladies and gentlemen,
please be warned,
this is the perfect blend
of the two
most dangerous creatures
that have ever walked
the Earth.
(HISSES)
We call it...
the Indoraptor.
- ♪ ♪
- (LOW GROWLING)
(GROWLS)
(GROWLING, HISSING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
- (SCREECHES)
- (ELECTRIC BUZZING)
(YELLING, GASPING)
The perfect weapon
for the modern age.
Built for combat, with
tactical responses more acute
- than any human soldier.
- What is that thing?
(SCREECHING, GROWLING)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(GROWLING, HUFFING)
(GROWLING)
MAISIE:
They made it.
- Mr. Mills and the other man.
- What man?
Him.
EVERSOLL:
Designed by Mr. Henry Wu,
with an intelligence quotient
comparable to the velociraptor,
biospecs include
a heightened sense of smell,
and trained to respond
to a pulse-coded
laser targeting system,
enabling it
to isolate and track prey
in complex environments.
Voilà!
(LOW WHIRRING GROWING LOUDER)
Now, first the laser sets
the target.
- (INDORAPTOR SNARLS)
- (PEOPLE GASPING)
And then once locked on,
the acoustic signal
triggers the attack.
- (ELECTRONIC SQUEALING)
- (SCREECHES)
(SCREAMING, GASPING)
- (EXCITED CHATTER)
- (CHUCKLES)
This animal is relentless.
Now, modifications
are still being made...
$20 millions!
(CROWD MURMURING)
EVERSOLL:
No, th-this is a-a prototype.
Uh, not for sale.
- 21!
- Well...
it is still a...
- a prototype, but...
- 22!
- (INDISTINCT SHOUTS)
- MAN: 23!
MAN 2:
24!
$24 million.
$25 millions!
Do I hear 26?
OWEN: That thing
can't leave this building.
- MAN: 26!
- EVERSOLL: Any advance on 26?
- 27. - $27 million dollars.
- What are you doing?
This animal is not for sale.
If you want
to create an addict,
you have to give them a taste.
He's a prototype.
Look, this prototype
is worth $28 million right now.
Relax. We'll make some more.
So will they.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING NEARBY)
(BELL DINGS)
(SCREECHES)
- (GRUNTS, GROANS)
- (METALLIC CLATTERING)
Hey, buddy.
You thinking what I'm thinking?
(GRUNTING)
EVERSOLL:
Once, twice...
- (GAVEL BANGS)
- Sold to the Russian friend.
(ROARING)
- A congratulations
- (BELL DINGS)
for this magnificent animal.
(CHITTERING)
- (GROWLS)
- (WOMAN SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING, PANICKED SHOUTS)
♪ ♪
(SNARLING)
(GROWLS)
(GRUNTING)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (PEOPLE SHOUTING)
- (YELLS)
- (ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTS CONTINUE)
(YELLING, GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
Get out of the way!
(GROWLS)
(YELLS)
- Go, go!
- Get this thing out of here!
(LOW GROWLING)
(ROARS)
(GRUNTS)
(LOW GROWLING)
♪ ♪
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING, SHOUTING)
- (SNARLS)
- (YELLS)
(TRUCK HORN BLARES)
WHEATLEY:
Mills!
Mills, where are you?!
I want my bonus!
(SNARLING, GROWLING)
Holy cow.
What are you?
I didn't see you on the island.
(SNARLS)
(GROWLING)
(SNARLING)
(SCREECHING)
Oh, you're a tough guy.
(HINGES CREAKING)
(BREATHING SOFTLY)
Look at you.
You're some kind of hot rod
with really pretty teeth.
This will make a perfect
centerpiece for my necklace.
(WHEATLEY GRUNTS QUIETLY)
(STRAINS):
Oh, boy.
- (SNARLS)
- (YELLING)
- (GROWLING)
- (YELLS)
- (CRUNCH)
- Aah!
(GROANING LOUDLY)
(WHEATLEY WHIMPERING)
(LOW GROWLING)
Oh...
(WEEPING)
- (SCREECHING)
- (SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS):
No!
(BONES CRUNCHING)
(WHEATLEY YELLING)
- (YELLING CONTINUES)
- (BONES CRUNCHING)
(WHEATLEY SCREAMS)
- Shh.
- (GRUNTS)
- (CHOMPING)
- Move! Move! Out of the way!
(SCREAMS)
(KEYPAD BEEPS)
(GROWLING)
(BEEPING)
(SNARLS)
(ECHOING THUMP)
(MUFFLED SNARLING)
(SIGHS, CHUCKLES)
(LOW GROWLING)
(ROARING)
- (SCREAMING)
- (GROWLING)
- (GUNS COCKING)
- MILLS: Don't!
You two,
you... deserve each other.
Maisie, come with me.
You got your money.
Now, walk away.
Oh, what are you gonna do, huh?
We're gonna stop this.
All of it.
How?! What, are you
gonna go back in time
before Hammond decided
to play God?
You can't put it
back in the box!
- We have to try.
- It's too late.
Maisie, come.
Oh...
so you're gonna take care
of her now, huh?
You have no idea what she is.
What do you think drove Hammond
and Lockwood apart? Huh?
Lockwood never had
a grandchild.
He just wanted
his daughter back.
- And he had the technology.
- (PANTING SOFTLY)
He created another.
He made her again.
- (MEN YELLING)
- (MAISIE SCREAMS)
- Go. - Go, go, go.
- (GROWLING, SNARLING)
(YELLING CONTINUES)
(MAISIE WHIMPERING, PANTING)
Come on!
- (SNARLING)
- Come on.
- ♪ ♪
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Get this to Mills.
Be very careful...
it's extremely valuable.
You... I need blood samples
from the raptor.
Don't just stand there
like an idiot!
Get me 50cc's carfentanil
and a phlebotomy kit!
It's right there! Now!
Come on, come on.
I need this raptor's blood.
- (SNARLS)
- Oh! For God...
Sure, go ahead.
Where is that kit?!
Okay, now, listen to me.
It is better for you
to cooperate.
I'm gonna get this blood,
with or without your help.
This blood's contaminated.
I designed this animal myself.
It's pure.
Every cell of her body
was created in the most
controlled environment,
- under the most demanding of conditions.
- (EXHALES)
Yeah, but I did an intravenous
blood transfusion
with a T. rex, so...
it's a sock drawer in there.
You what?
- (GASPS)
- Whoa! Frank! What are you doing?!
- (SCREECHING)
- Saving your life.
Yes...!
MAN:
Stop!
- Don't move.
- (ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
(GROWLING, SNARLING)
Now, step away from that cage.
Now.
(GROWLING)
(SNARLING)
- (SCREECHING)
- Easy, now.
(ELECTRICAL CRACKLING)
(GRUNTS, SCREECHES)
- Oh! (GRUNTING)
- (CRACKLING)
- (CRUNCHING BITE)
- (YELLING)
(YELLING CONTINUES)
(HISSING)
(SCREECHES)
- (YELLING, SCREAMING)
- (FRANKLIN GASPS)
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
(LOUD CRUNCH)
Run. Run!
(CRACKLING, HISSING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(SNIFFS, GASPS)
- (BELLOWING)
- (EXPLOSION)
(POWER WHIRRING DOWN)
(BEEPING)
(DISTANT THUNDER RUMBLING)
(HINGES CREAKING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(DISTANT THUNDER CRASHES)
- (ALL GASP)
- (LOW GROWLING)
(CHOMPING)
(TAPPING)
(HISSES)
- (HUFFS)
- (MAISIE GASPS SOFTLY)
(HUFFS)
(CREAKING NEARBY)
(SNIFFING)
(HUFFS)
- (SQUEALING)
- MAN (OVER RADIO): Dave, you copy?
- Dave, you there?
- (SNARLS)
Run!
♪ ♪
(SNARLS)
(SCREAMS)
(OWEN GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SNIFFING)
(HINGES CREAK QUIETLY)
(LOW SNARLING)
(CLATTERING)
- (SNARLING)
- (CLATTERING)
(LOUD GROWLING)
- (OBJECTS CLATTER)
- (GROWLS)
(POWER WHIRRING DOWN)
(ALARM BLARING)
(PANTING):
You see that?
ZIA:
That's hydrogen cyanide.
If it reaches
the containment level,
it'll kill them all.
The ventilation system is down.
Can you bring it back up?
(THUMPING STEP IN DISTANCE)
(TAPPING IN DISTANCE)
(DISTANT THUNDER CRASHING)
(LOW GROWL)
(ALARM CONTINUES BLARING)
(BELLOWS)
(KEYBOARD CLATTERING)
(SIGHS)
The server's unresponsive.
I have to reboot
the whole system.
- So reboot it.
- I'm trying.
(LOW GROWLING NEARBY)
(DISTANT THUNDER RUMBLING)
(WHISPERS):
What?
Franklin, we don't have time.
I know, I know, I know.
Okay.
(POWER WHIRRING)
♪ ♪
(BREATH SHUDDERING)
- (THUNDER CRASHING)
- (SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
(CLAIRE SCREAMS)
(SCREAMS)
(OWEN GRUNTING)
Come on. Go! Go, run, run!
- (SCREAMS)
- (YELLS)
(CLAIRE CRIES OUT)
(SCREAMS)
(SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
(MAISIE SCREAMS)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING BREATHS)
(SCREECHES)
(STRAINED GRUNTING)
- (GRUNTS, GASPS)
- Hey.
- (PANTING LOUDLY)
- You're okay.
Put pressure on it.
Don't look at it.
Look at me. Look at me.
You have to go find her.
I can't leave you here.
Go. I'll be fine.
Run!
♪ ♪
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(PANTING)
♪ ♪
(HUFFING BREATHS)
(ROARING)
(GASPS)
- (WOOD CREAKING)
- (WHIMPERING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
(THUNDER CRACKS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(DISTANT SCREECHING)
(PANTING, TREMBLING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(GASPS, PANTS)
(MAISIE WHIMPERING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(HINGES CREAKING)
(TAPPING)
(WHIMPERING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(MAISIE PANTING FRANTICALLY)
(MAISIE'S SUPPRESSED SCREAMING)
(LOW GROWLING)
- Maisie! Stay down!
- (SNARLS)
(SHRIEKING IN PAIN)
(LOW GROWLING)
(BULLETS CLATTERING)
(WEAPON CLICKS)
(WEAK SCREECHING)
(SNARLS)
(LOW GROWLING)
(HISSING NEARBY)
(SCREECHING)
(GROWLING)
(MAISIE SCREAMS)
Shh.
(JAWS SNAP)
(MAISIE SHRIEKS)
(SCREECHES)
Follow me.
I know a way on the other side.
- (SNARLING, GROWLING)
- Come on.
Come on!
(MAISIE SCREAMS)
(SNARLING)
(MAISIE WHIMPERS)
This way!
♪ ♪
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(CRACKLING)
(LOW GROWLING)
(SCREECHES)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
I got ya!
(MAISIE GRUNTS)
- (STRAINED GRUNT)
- (CRACKLING)
(REPEATED CLANGING NEARBY)
Hey!
(ROARS)
(GRUNTS)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(HUFFS)
(PANTS)
(LOW WHIRRING)
(GROWLS)
(ELECTRONIC SQUEALING)
(SCREECHES)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREECHING)
(GROWLS)
(HUFFING)
♪ ♪
(SCREECHES)
(LOW GROWLING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(BLUE SCREECHES)
♪ ♪
(SHRIEKS)
(GROWLING MOAN)
(SCREECHES)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
♪ ♪
(EXHALES)
What the hell?
(BOTH PANTING)
OWEN:
Hey!
FRANKLIN:
(EXHALES) Hey!
You good?
Yeah. You?
- Nope.
- Hey, we got a problem downstairs.
I need you to come see this.
(ALARM BLARING)
(BELLOWS)
(ROARS)
(DISTANT BELLOWING)
(BELLOWING CONTINUES)
They're all dying.
The blast damaged
the ventilation system.
We did everything we could.
I can open the gates from here.
OWEN:
Claire.
Be careful.
We're not on an island anymore.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
(CLANGING)
(ROARS)
(BELLOWING)
- (ROARS)
- (GATE CREAKS)
(ROARING)
- (BELLOWING)
- (GASPS)
♪ ♪
- (CLANGING)
- (BELLOWING)
(BELLOWS)
(BELLOWING)
OWEN:
Claire.
You press that button,
there is no going back.
♪ ♪
We can't let them die.
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
- (ROARING)
- (BELLOWING)
(ROARING)
(DOOR CLANGS LOUDLY)
(GASPS)
I had to.
They're alive, like me.
♪ ♪
(DISTANT RUMBLING)
(DISTANT RUMBLING GROWS LOUDER)
(SHRIEKS)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
No! No!
(GASPS)
(CHITTERING)
(ROARING, BELLOWING)
(SCREAMS)
(YELLS)
(DINOSAUR ROARING)
(YELLING)
(AIR HISSES)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
Aah!
(ROARING, GALLOPING QUIETS)
(PANTING)
(CHITTERING)
(SCREECHING)
- (ROARING)
- (MILLS SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARS)
(ROARING LOUDLY)
(CHITTERING)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
- (SNORTING NEARBY)
- (GASPS)
Hey, girl.
- CLAIRE: Owen.
- (SHUSHES)
(BLUE PURRING)
It's okay.
She won't hurt us.
(PURRING)
(BLUE PANTING)
Hey.
(BLUE PURRS)
Blue, come with me.
We'll take you
to a safe place, okay?
(PURRING)
(SHRIEKS)
(CHITTERS)
(SHRIEKS IN DISTANCE)
MALCOLM:
How many times
do you have to
see the evidence?
How many times
must the point be made?
(ROARING)
We're causing
our own extinction.
Too many red lines
have been crossed.
And our home has,
in fundamental ways,
been polluted by
avarice and political
megalomania.
Genetic power has now
been unleashed,
and of course,
that's gonna be catastrophic.
This change was inevitable
from the moment we brought
the first dinosaur
back from extinction.
(ROARS)
We convince ourselves
that sudden change
is something that happens
outside the normal order
of things,
like a... car crash,
or that it's beyond
our control,
like a fatal illness.
We don't conceive of sudden,
radical, irrational change
as woven into the very fabric
of existence.
Yet, I can assure you,
it most assuredly is.
And it's happening now.
Humans and dinosaurs are now
gonna be forced to coexist.
(BELLOWS)
These creatures were here
before us.
And if we're not careful,
they're gonna be here after.
(BOTH ROARING)
We're gonna have to adjust
to new threats
that we can't imagine.
(SCREECHING)
We've entered a new era.
Welcome to Jurassic World.
♪ ♪
(SNIFFING)
(YELPING)
♪ ♪
(SCREECHING)
(HORNS HONKING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SCREECHING CONTINUES)
Subtitles by explosiveskull